Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're back in the office.
今天我们回到办公室。
We have a lesson that's talking about something that goes wrong in the office.
这节课讲的是办公室里出问题的事情。
Yes, something that I can really understand well, but we'll talk about that later.
是的，有些事我深有体会，不过我们稍后再聊。
So this lesson is about a photocopier.
所以这节课是关于复印机的。
A photocopier.
复印机。
So let's take a look at this word in vocabulary preview.
我们先来看看词汇预览中的这个词。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
All right, so a photocopier makes copies.
好的，复印机就是用来复印的。
Yeah, it makes copies of documents.
对，复印文件。
We often call it a copier or a copy machine.
我们常叫它copier或copy machine。
Yeah, so you can call it a photocopier, copy machine or copier.
是的，你可以叫它photocopier、copy machine或copier。
Yes, or a Xerox machine as well.
对，或者Xerox机器。
Xerox machine.
施乐机。
Yeah, we can talk about that a little bit later because that's an interesting story.
嗯，我们可以稍后聊聊这个，因为那是个有趣的故事。
Okay.
好的。
All right, let's take a look at our next word.
好了，我们来看下一个词。
Toner.
碳粉。
Toner is what the copy machine uses to make copies.
碳粉是复印机用来复印的东西。
It's like the ink.
就像墨水一样。
Right.
对。
It's a very fine black powder.
它是一种很细的黑色粉末。
Oh.
哦。
Yeah, yeah.
对，对。
So it's not an ink.
所以它不是墨水。
No, it's actually dry.
不，它实际上是干的。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah, yeah.
对，对。
It's dry.
它是干的。
It's a powder, so you don't want to get that all over you.
它是粉末，所以别弄得到处都是。
All right.
好的。
Well, good advice, Marco.
嗯，好建议，Marco。
And our last word in vocabulary preview, malfunction.
词汇预览中的最后一个词，故障。
Malfunction.
故障。
Let's break down this word.
我们来分解这个词。
All right.
好的。
Malfunction is to work.
“malfunction”是“工作”的意思。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
All right.
好的。
Mal.
“mal”。
I guess mal maybe comes from Latin or something because in Spanish we say mal, which is something
我猜“mal”可能来自拉丁语，因为在西班牙语里我们说“mal”，意思是邪恶或不好的东西。
evil or not good.
邪恶或不好的东西。
Okay.
好的。
So I think we can understand malfunction is not good working.
所以我们可以理解“malfunction”就是工作不正常。
Right?
对吧？
Yeah.
对。
Okay.
好的。
More or less, it's not working properly.
差不多，就是不能正常工作。
Not working properly.
不能正常工作。
Yeah.
对。
Right.
Okay.
好的。
Let's find out what isn't working properly.
我们来看看什么东西不能正常工作。
Hey, Carl, can you make a copy of this contract for me, please?
嘿，Carl，你能帮我复印这份合同吗？
And when you have it ready, send it out ASAP to our sub branch.
弄好后，尽快发到我们的分公司。
Sure.
好的。
I think I broke this thing.
我想我把这东西弄坏了。
Maxine, can you help me out here?
Maxine，你能帮我看看吗？
I'm not really a tech guy.
我不是很懂技术。
Yeah, sure.
好的，当然。
I think it's just out of toner.
我想只是碳粉用完了。
You can go use the other one upstairs.
你可以去楼上用另一台。
On your way up, can you fax this while I try and fix this thing?
你上去的时候，能帮我把这个传真发了吗？我试着修修这东西。
Damn it.
该死。
Everything in this office seems to be breaking down.
这办公室里好像什么东西都在坏。
I'll send the stupid fax later.
我待会儿再发那个破传真。
Oh, great.
哦，太好了。
Is someone playing a practical joke on me?
有人在跟我搞恶作剧吗？
This is ridiculous.
这太荒谬了。
The elevator has some sort of malfunction.
电梯出了某种故障。
Just take the stairs, dude.
走楼梯吧，哥们。
What floor are you going to?
你要去几楼？
I have to go up 15 floors.
我得上去15层。
Never mind.
算了。
Made it.
到了。
There's a copier.
有台复印机。
No!
不！
Okay, so this copy machine is definitely not working properly.
好吧，这台复印机肯定不能正常工作了。
A serious malfunction.
严重的故障。
I think the whole building exploded.
我觉得整栋楼都爆炸了。
All right, very dramatic here at EnglishPod, but we have fun, right?
好吧，EnglishPod这里很戏剧化，但我们玩得很开心，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, let's take a look at some of the great language that we saw in Language Takeaway.
好的，我们来看看“语言要点”里的一些精彩语言。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, three words for you here in Language Takeaway, and we heard all of these in the
好的，“语言要点”里有三个词，我们在对话中都听到了。
dialogue.
对话中。
So this guy needs to get a copy ASAP.
所以这家伙需要尽快拿到复印件。
ASAP.
尽快。
Or ASAP.
或者ASAP。
Yes, meaning?
是的，意思是？
As soon as possible.
尽快。
So really, really fast.
所以非常非常快。
Yeah.
对。
This is a very, very common phrase, right?
这是一个非常非常常见的短语，对吧？
So it's an acronym, and you can say it like ASAP or?
所以它是一个首字母缩略词，你可以说成ASAP或者？
ASAP.
ASAP。
Exactly.
没错。
Yeah, usually people say it like that because it's too long, I guess, to say as soon as
对，通常人们这么说，因为说“as soon as possible”太长了。
possible.
可能吧。
So, hey, I need this document ASAP.
所以，嘿，我尽快需要这份文件。
Yes.
是的。
Or ASAP.
或者ASAP。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, let's look at our next word.
好的，我们来看下一个词。
A practical joke.
恶作剧。
Practical joke.
Okay, so a practical joke, I'm sure we have all played a practical joke on some of our
好的，恶作剧，我相信我们都对朋友搞过恶作剧，对吧？
friends, right?
是的。
Yes.
基本上，就是故意对某人做些有趣的事。
Basically, what you do is you do something funny on purpose to someone.
对，但有点疯狂。
Yeah, but something crazy.
疯狂，对吧？
Crazy, right?
对。
Yeah.
For example, when I was in university, there was this guy in our building, and we took
例如，我上大学的时候，我们楼里有个家伙，我们把他卧室里所有的家具，床、书桌什么的，都搬到了足球场上。
all of his bedroom furniture, so his bed, his desk, everything, and put it down on the
所有的家具。
football field.
足球场上。
Nice.
不错。
Yeah, that was a practical joke.
对，那就是个恶作剧。
That is a very good and elaborate practical joke.
那是个非常精心策划的恶作剧。
Yeah.
对。
Okay, so practical joke, do something crazy or funny to your friends.
好的，所以恶作剧就是对朋友做些疯狂或有趣的事。
Okay.
好的。
And now let's look at our last word.
现在我们来看最后一个词。
Never mind.
算了。
Okay, so if you say never mind, it means...
好的，如果你说“never mind”，意思是……
Don't worry about it.
别担心。
Forget it.
忘了它吧。
Yeah.
对。
Never mind.
算了。
Yeah.
对。
Yeah, this is, you know, this is so common, and I think it would be helpful to understand
对，这个非常常见，我觉得了解它的用法会很有帮助。
how it's used.
用法。
So let's hear some examples.
我们来听一些例子。
Example one.
例子一。
Someone stole my wallet.
有人偷了我的钱包。
Oh, wait.
哦，等等。
Never mind.
算了。
Here it is.
在这儿呢。
Example two.
例子二。
Can you get some milk on your way home?
你回家路上能买点牛奶吗？
Oh, never mind.
哦，算了。
We still have some.
我们还有一些。
Example three.
例子三。
The printer's broken?
打印机坏了？
Never mind.
算了。
I'll do this later.
我晚点再做。
Okay, great examples, and I think our language takeaway is clear.
好的，很好的例子，我觉得我们的“语言要点”很清楚了。
So why don't we listen to our dialogue for the second time, and then we'll come back
那我们再听一遍对话，然后回来聊聊“融会贯通”。
and talk about putting it together.
聊聊“融会贯通”。
Hey, Carl, can you make a copy of this contract for me, please?
嘿，Carl，你能帮我复印这份合同吗？
And when you have it ready, send it out ASAP to our sub-branch.
弄好后，尽快发到我们的分公司。
Sure.
好的。
I think I broke this thing.
我想我把这东西弄坏了。
Maxine, can you help me out here?
Maxine，你能帮我看看吗？
I'm not really a tech guy.
我不是很懂技术。
Yeah, sure.
好的，当然。
I think it's just out of toner.
我想只是碳粉用完了。
You can go use the other one upstairs.
你可以去楼上用另一台。
On your way up, can you fax this while I try and fix this thing?
你上去的时候，能帮我把这个传真发了吗？我试着修修这东西。
Sure.
好的。
Damn it.
该死。
Everything in this office seems to be breaking down.
这办公室里好像什么东西都在坏。
I'll send the stupid fax later.
我待会儿再发那个破传真。
Oh, great!
哦，太好了！
Is someone playing a practical joke on me?
有人在跟我搞恶作剧吗？
This is ridiculous!
这太荒谬了！
The elevator has some sort of malfunction.
电梯出了某种故障。
Just take the stairs, dude.
走楼梯吧，哥们。
What floor are you going to?
你要去几楼？
I have to go up 15 floors!
我得上去15层！
Never mind.
算了。
Made it.
到了。
There's the copier.
有台复印机。
No!
不！
In this episode, we're going to learn how to use the computer to make a copy of a contract.
在这一集里，我们将学习如何使用电脑复印合同。
In this dialogue, there's some great language that can be used in many different patterns
在这个对话中，有一些很棒的语言可以用在很多不同的模式里。
or in many different ways.
或者很多不同的方式。
So, in today's Putting It Together, we're going to show you how to use three of these
所以，在今天的“融会贯通”中，我们将向你展示如何使用其中三种模式。
patterns.
如何使用其中三种模式。
Putting It Together
融会贯通
Okay, the first pattern that we can look at is out of toner.
好的，我们可以看的第一个模式是“碳粉用完了”。
Out of toner.
碳粉用完了。
Right.
对。
So, we already talked about toner.
那么，我们已经讨论过 toner（墨粉）了。
Let's talk about out of.
我们来谈谈 out of。
Okay, so when you are out of, you have none.
好的，所以当你 out of 某物时，就是没有了。
Right.
对。
So, let's change a little bit.
那么，我们稍微变一下。
So, I can say, I am out of milk.
所以，我可以说，I am out of milk（我没牛奶了）。
I'm out of time.
I'm out of time（我没时间了）。
Out of time, right?
Out of time，对吧？
If you're driving, I'm out of gas or gasoline.
如果你在开车，I'm out of gas or gasoline（我没油了）。
Yep.
嗯。
So, out of plus noun.
所以，out of 加名词。
Perfect.
完美。
It means you don't have none.
意思是你没有了。
EnglishPod.com.
EnglishPod.com。
You ain't got none.
你一点都没有了。
Eubonics.com.
Eubonics.com。
All right.
好了。
Out of time.
Out of time（没时间了）。
Let's take a look at our second one.
我们来看看第二个短语。
On your way up.
On your way up（在你上去的路上）。
Yeah, on your way up.
对，on your way up。
On your way, right?
On your way，对吧？
So, this is a great way when you are talking to someone and they're going somewhere.
所以，当你跟某人说话，而他们要去某个地方时，这是个很好的表达方式。
Yes.
是的。
Right?
对吧？
So, on your way up.
所以，on your way up。
Can you bring this to HR?
你能把这个带到人力资源部吗？
Okay.
好的。
On your way to the store.
在你去商店的路上。
Can you mail this letter?
你能寄这封信吗？
Or maybe on your way home.
或者在你回家的路上。
Can you buy me some flowers?
你能给我买些花吗？
Nice.
不错。
All right.
好了。
So, on your way, it means...
所以，on your way 的意思是……
It means while you are going there.
意思是在你去那里的路上。
Right.
对。
Yeah.
是的。
Taking advantage of the fact that you are going somewhere.
利用你要去某个地方这个事实。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
Now, let's take a look at our last one.
现在，我们来看看最后一个短语。
And this is a really great phrase.
这真是个很棒的短语。
Break down.
Break down（出故障）。
Break down。
In our dialogue, we heard breaking down.
在我们的对话中，我们听到了 breaking down。
Yes.
是的。
Right?
对吧？
Everything in the office seems to be breaking down.
办公室里的一切似乎都在出故障。
Right.
对。
So, when something breaks down...
所以，当某物 break down 时……
It stops working.
它停止工作了。
Yeah.
是的。
Exactly.
没错。
So, we can change it a little bit.
所以，我们可以稍微变一下。
So, what if we say, break up?
那么，如果我们说 break up（分手）呢？
Ooh, boyfriend and girlfriend.
哦，男朋友和女朋友。
Right.
对。
They end their relationship.
他们结束了关系。
Okay.
好的。
So, we can maybe think about it as their relationship stops working.
所以，我们可以把它理解为他们的关系停止运作了。
Oh, nice one.
哦，说得好。
Right?
对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
What about break in?
那 break in（闯入）呢？
Enter a place using force.
用武力进入一个地方。
Right.
对。
You enter a house that's not yours.
你进入一个不属于你的房子。
Yeah.
是的。
So, if you break into a house, maybe you break the window and climb in.
所以，如果你 break into 一栋房子，也许你打破窗户爬进去。
Okay.
好的。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
What about break out?
那 break out（越狱）呢？
The opposite.
相反的意思。
Right.
对。
So, break out of jail.
所以，break out of jail（越狱）。
Break out of prison.
Break out of prison（越狱）。
Yeah.
是的。
So, this is a great phrase.
所以，这是个很棒的短语。
You can change the last word from break down, break up, break in, and it means different
你可以改变最后一个词，从 break down、break up、break in，意思就不同了。
things.
事情。
Yeah.
是的。
So, use different prepositions for different meanings.
所以，用不同的介词来表达不同的意思。
Perfect.
完美。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
Okay.
好的。
So, now let's listen to our dialogue for the last time, and then Erica and I will be back
那么，现在让我们最后一次听对话，然后我和 Erica 会回来。
and talk a little bit more about malfunctioning office supplies.
再聊聊关于出故障的办公用品。
Hey, Carl, can you make a copy of this contract for me, please?
嘿，Carl，你能帮我复印这份合同吗？
And when you have it ready, send it out ASAP to our sub-branch.
等你准备好后，尽快发到我们的分公司。
Sure.
当然。
I think I missed it.
我想我搞砸了。
I'm sorry.
对不起。
I think I broke this thing.
我想我把这东西弄坏了。
Maxine, can you help me out here?
Maxine，你能帮我一下吗？
I'm not really a tech guy.
我不是很懂技术。
Yeah, sure.
好的，当然。
I think it's just out of toner.
我想只是 toner（墨粉）用完了。
You can go use the other one upstairs.
你可以去楼上用另一台。
On your way up, can you fax this while I try and fix this thing?
在你上去的路上，能帮我传真这个吗，我试着修这东西。
Sure.
当然。
Damn it!
该死！
Everything in this office seems to be breaking down.
这办公室里的一切似乎都在出故障。
I'll send the stupid fax later.
我晚点再发那该死的传真。
Oh great!
哦，太好了！
Is someone playing a practical joke on me?
有人在跟我开玩笑吗？
This is ridiculous!
这太荒谬了！
The elevator has some sort of malfunction.
电梯出了某种故障。
Just take the stairs dude.
走楼梯吧，老兄。
What floor are you going to?
你要去几楼？
I have to go up 15 floors!
我要上15层楼！
Never mind.
算了。
Made it.
到了。
There's the copier.
复印机在那儿。
No!
不！
Alright, so Erica, everything that you touch that's electronic seems to malfunction, right?
好了，Erica，你碰过的所有电子设备似乎都会出故障，对吧？
This is absolutely true.
这绝对是真的。
I don't know what it is, but you know what, if I turn on a computer it will suddenly get
我不知道为什么，但你知道吗，如果我打开一台电脑，它就会突然。
a virus.
中病毒。
And even if I'm very careful it still breaks.
即使我很小心，它还是会坏。
Right.
对。
Yeah, it happens sometimes.
是的，有时候会这样。
I can relate to that.
我深有体会。
But you are much better at computers and technology than I am.
但你在电脑和技术方面比我强多了。
Well, I really, really like them.
嗯，我真的很喜欢它们。
And well, I guess even I know a little bit about copy machines or copiers because my
而且，我想我甚至对复印机或复印机了解一点，因为。
uncles are like copy technicians.
我的叔叔们是复印机技术员。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah, so they fix copiers that broke down or they replace toner and they do all that
是的，所以他们修理出故障的复印机，或者更换墨粉，做所有这些。
stuff so that's why I know a little bit about it.
事情，所以这就是为什么我了解一点。
But actually the original term is a Xerox machine.
但实际上，原来的术语是 Xerox machine（施乐复印机）。
Yes, why is that?
是的，为什么？
From the brand, right?
来自品牌，对吧？
Ah, right.
啊，对。
There's a brand called Xerox and Xerox invented and patented this technology of making copies.
有一个品牌叫 Xerox，Xerox 发明并专利了这种复印技术。
Alright well the next time my photocopier explodes I'll call you.
好了，下次我的复印机爆炸了，我会打电话给你。
Call my uncles, right?
打给我叔叔，对吧？
Alright and well let us know how things in your office break down or if you have any
好了，请告诉我们你办公室里的东西是怎么出故障的，或者如果你有。
stories of like Erica that breaks everything she touches.
像 Erica 那样碰什么坏什么的故事。
It's true.
这是真的。
Alright, so come to our website, come to our comment section and leave your opinions and
好了，所以来我们的网站，来我们的评论区，留下你的意见。
we'll be there to also answer any doubts or questions you might have.
我们也会在那里回答你可能有的任何疑问或问题。
That's right.
没错。
You can find us at EnglishPod.com and Marco and I are always around.
你可以在 EnglishPod.com 找到我们，Marco 和我总是在。
Alright so we'll see you guys there.
好了，我们到时候见。
Yep, we will.
是的，我们会。
Okay guys, thanks for listening and until next time.
好了，各位，感谢收听，下次再见。
Bye.
再见。